## **Andre Gao**

#### WEB DEVELOPER

Portfolio: andregao.com GitHub: /andregao LinkedIn: /andregao Skill IQs: /andregao

Austin, TX 78729 (702) 981-7446 andregao@me.com

### **PROFILE**

A self-taught full-stack Javascript developer that's passionate about learning technology and building things. Co-founded an international group buying company that won TechCrunch Disrupt Beijing 2011. Started programming career in 2018 but have a decade of tech start-up experiences

## **EDUCATION**

# Angular Web Developer React Web Developer

Pluralsight RoleIQ Level 2

Pluralsight.com - 2019

## Bachelor of Information System Bachelor of Management

University of Tasmania Shanghai Ocean University

Shanghai, China 2004 - 2008

## **SKILLS**

- Javascript, TypeScript
- React, Redux, Gatsby, GraphQL
- Angular, NgRx, RxJS
- Node.js, Express, GCP Firebase
- HTML, CSS, SASS

### **PROJECTS**

#### watchtv.web.app

A TV show tracker

A full stack web application built with React, Redux, Material-UI, RxJS, and Express. It pulls entertainment data from public APIs and communicates with serverless functions to access user database. The app utilizes React function components and hooks, Observables for Redux async actions, and Firebase auth library for JWT and OAuth integrations

#### thangs.web.app

A practical list app

A data-driven Angular project that uses Redux state management to centralize client-side data, interacts with a real-time NoSQL database and authenticates users using Google OAuth and email/password

#### andregao.com

Portfolio website

Built with Angular Material and Flex-layout. A front end focused project that implements modern Web APIs, CSS Flexbox, responsive design, and explores the view mechanics in Angular

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Intern Web Developer**

Indieparty Co. - Las Vegas, NV 2018

Reviewed code base and developer documentations, implemented best practices and collaboration techniques from the development team, and learned from tech lead on scaffolding and scaling a production Angular application

#### Co-Founder, VP of Sourcing

OrderWithMe / WithMe Inc.- China & Las Vegas, NV 2011-2017

Led a sourcing team of 7 and brought product ideas from concepts to mass productions. Supervised manufacturing lifecycles from prototyping and samples to quality control and logistics. Shipped dozens of containers to the US. Developed and managed multiple private label programs and supply chain operations across a variety of industries

#### **Technical Director**

Nihaoareyou Inc. - Shanghai, China 2009-2011

Managed production and post-production teams and daily creative operations, recruited and coached crew and editors, created visual effects and oversaw translations for all website content

#### **Technical Manager**

Shangby Inc. - Shanghai, China 2008

Managed pre-production crew and operation, ran live shopping event broadcasts, created newsletters, maintained e-commerce site and in charge of our affiliate marketing program